let secondConditionalQuiz = [
  {
    question: `Complete the second conditional sentence: "If they had more time, they ______ go on vacation."`,
    options: {
      A: "would",
      B: "will",
      C: "would have",
      D: "will have",
    },
    correctAnswer: "would",
    explanation: `In the second conditional, use "would" to indicate the result of a hypothetical condition. Thus, "If they had more time, they would go on vacation."`,
  },
  {
    question: `Which of the following sentences is an example of the second conditional?`,
    options: {
      A: "If he were taller, he would play basketball.",
      B: "If he is taller, he would play basketball.",
      C: "If he were taller, he will play basketball.",
      D: "If he had been taller, he would play basketball.",
    },
    correctAnswer: "If he were taller, he would play basketball.",
    explanation: `The second conditional describes hypothetical or unreal situations in the present or future using "past simple" and "would."`,
  },
  {
    question: `Complete the second conditional sentence: "If I had a car, I ______ drive to work."`,
    options: {
      A: "would",
      B: "will",
      C: "would have",
      D: "will have",
    },
    correctAnswer: "would",
    explanation: `In the second conditional, use "would" to express the result of a hypothetical situation. Therefore, "If I had a car, I would drive to work."`,
  },
  {
    question: `Which sentence correctly demonstrates the second conditional?`,
    options: {
      A: "If you spoke French, you would understand the movie.",
      B: "If you speak French, you would understand the movie.",
      C: "If you spoke French, you will understand the movie.",
      D: "If you had spoken French, you would understand the movie.",
    },
    correctAnswer: "If you spoke French, you would understand the movie.",
    explanation: `The second conditional is used for hypothetical situations in the present or future. Use "past simple" and "would" for the result.`,
  },
  {
    question: `Choose the correct second conditional sentence:`,
    options: {
      A: "If it were sunny, we would go to the beach.",
      B: "If it is sunny, we would go to the beach.",
      C: "If it were sunny, we will go to the beach.",
      D: "If it had been sunny, we would go to the beach.",
    },
    correctAnswer: "If it were sunny, we would go to the beach.",
    explanation: `The second conditional uses "past simple" in the if-clause and "would" in the main clause to describe hypothetical situations.`,
  },
  {
    question: `Complete the second conditional sentence: "If she were the president, she ______ change the law."`,
    options: {
      A: "would",
      B: "will",
      C: "would have",
      D: "will have",
    },
    correctAnswer: "would",
    explanation: `In the second conditional, use "would" to express the hypothetical result. Hence, "If she were the president, she would change the law."`,
  },
  {
    question: `Which of the following sentences uses the second conditional correctly?`,
    options: {
      A: "If I had the chance, I would learn to play the guitar.",
      B: "If I have the chance, I would learn to play the guitar.",
      C: "If I had the chance, I will learn to play the guitar.",
      D: "If I had had the chance, I would learn to play the guitar.",
    },
    correctAnswer: "If I had the chance, I would learn to play the guitar.",
    explanation: `The second conditional uses "past simple" and "would" to discuss unreal or hypothetical situations.`,
  },
  {
    question: `Complete the second conditional sentence: "If we lived closer, we ______ see each other more often."`,
    options: {
      A: "would",
      B: "will",
      C: "would have",
      D: "will have",
    },
    correctAnswer: "would",
    explanation: `The second conditional is used to describe hypothetical situations. Use "would" to express the result of the condition. Thus, "If we lived closer, we would see each other more often."`,
  },
  {
    question: `Which sentence correctly uses the second conditional?`,
    options: {
      A: "If they had known about the party, they would have come.",
      B: "If they know about the party, they would come.",
      C: "If they knew about the party, they would come.",
      D: "If they knew about the party, they will come.",
    },
    correctAnswer: "If they knew about the party, they would come.",
    explanation: `The second conditional uses "past simple" and "would" to describe hypothetical or unreal situations in the present or future.`,
  },
  {
    question: `Complete the second conditional sentence: "If you were the boss, you ______ make different decisions."`,
    options: {
      A: "would",
      B: "will",
      C: "would have",
      D: "will have",
    },
    correctAnswer: "would",
    explanation: `In the second conditional, use "would" to indicate the result of a hypothetical situation. Hence, "If you were the boss, you would make different decisions."`,
  },
  {
    question: `Which of the following is a correct second conditional sentence?`,
    options: {
      A: "If he were more careful, he would not make so many mistakes.",
      B: "If he was more careful, he would not make so many mistakes.",
      C: "If he were more careful, he will not make so many mistakes.",
      D: "If he had been more careful, he would not make so many mistakes.",
    },
    correctAnswer:
      "If he were more careful, he would not make so many mistakes.",
    explanation: `The second conditional uses "past simple" and "would" to describe hypothetical or unreal situations in the present or future.`,
  },
  {
    question: `Complete the second conditional sentence: "If I knew his number, I ______ call him."`,
    options: {
      A: "would",
      B: "will",
      C: "would have",
      D: "will have",
    },
    correctAnswer: "would",
    explanation: `In the second conditional, use "would" to express the result of a hypothetical situation. Therefore, "If I knew his number, I would call him."`,
  },
  {
    question: `Which sentence correctly demonstrates the second conditional?`,
    options: {
      A: "If we had a larger house, we would host more parties.",
      B: "If we have a larger house, we would host more parties.",
      C: "If we had a larger house, we will host more parties.",
      D: "If we had had a larger house, we would host more parties.",
    },
    correctAnswer: "If we had a larger house, we would host more parties.",
    explanation: `The second conditional uses "past simple" and "would" to discuss hypothetical situations in the present or future.`,
  },
  {
    question: `Complete the second conditional sentence: "If they were invited, they ______ come to the wedding."`,
    options: {
      A: "would",
      B: "will",
      C: "would have",
      D: "will have",
    },
    correctAnswer: "would",
    explanation: `In the second conditional, use "would" to indicate the result of a hypothetical condition. Thus, "If they were invited, they would come to the wedding."`,
  },
  {
    question: `Which of the following sentences is an example of the second conditional?`,
    options: {
      A: "If she spoke Spanish, she would be able to help us.",
      B: "If she speaks Spanish, she would be able to help us.",
      C: "If she spoke Spanish, she will be able to help us.",
      D: "If she had spoken Spanish, she would be able to help us.",
    },
    correctAnswer: "If she spoke Spanish, she would be able to help us.",
    explanation: `The second conditional uses "past simple" and "would" to describe hypothetical or unreal situations.`,
  },
];

let quiz_container = document.getElementById("quizContainer");
let result_div = document.getElementById("result");
let result_container = document.getElementById("resultText"); // Correctly targets the #resultText element
let submit_quiz = document.getElementById("submit");
let reset_quiz = document.getElementById("reset");

// Shuffle function for randomizing questions
function shuffle(array) {
  for (let i = array.length - 1; i > 0; i--) {
    const j = Math.floor(Math.random() * (i + 1));
    [array[i], array[j]] = [array[j], array[i]];
  }
  return array;
}

shuffle(secondConditionalQuiz);

// Display questions dynamically
function display_questions() {
  secondConditionalQuiz.forEach((element, index) => {
    let questionNumber = index + 1;
    let question_div = document.createElement("div");
    question_div.id = "questionsDiv";

    question_div.innerHTML = `<h2 id="questionNumberAndQuestion">${questionNumber}. ${element.question}</h2>`;

    quiz_container.appendChild(question_div);
    let options_div = document.createElement("div");
    options_div.id = "optionsDiv";

    for (const [key, value] of Object.entries(element.options)) {
      let options_inner_div = document.createElement("div");
      options_inner_div.id = "optionsInnerDiv";
      let radio_button = document.createElement("input");
      radio_button.type = "radio";
      radio_button.name = `question${index}`;
      radio_button.id = `radioButton-${index}-${key}`;
      radio_button.value = value;
      let label = document.createElement("label");
      label.textContent = `${key}: ${value}`;

      options_inner_div.appendChild(radio_button);
      question_div.appendChild(options_div);
      options_inner_div.appendChild(label);
      options_div.appendChild(options_inner_div);
    }
    let explanation = document.createElement("div");
    explanation.classList = "explanation";

    explanation.style.display = "none";
    question_div.appendChild(explanation);
  });
}
display_questions();

// Submit quiz and calculate score
submit_quiz.addEventListener("click", function () {
  let score = 0;
  let questions = secondConditionalQuiz.length;
  result_container.innerHTML = ""; // Clear previous results

  secondConditionalQuiz.forEach((element, index) => {
    let radio_button = document.querySelector(
      `input[name="question${index}"]:checked`
    );

    let explanation = document.querySelectorAll(".explanation")[index];
    explanation.style.display = "block";

    if (radio_button) {
      if (radio_button.value === element.correctAnswer) {
        score++;
        explanation.style.color = "green";
        explanation.innerHTML = `<p>Correct! - "${element.correctAnswer}" is the right answer</p><p>Explanation: ${element.explanation}</p>`;
      } else {
        explanation.style.color = "red";
        explanation.innerHTML = `<p>Incorrect! - "${element.correctAnswer}" is the right answer</p><p>Explanation: ${element.explanation}<p/>`;
      }
    } else {
      explanation.innerHTML = `<p>No Answer Selected</p><p>The correct answer is: ${element.correctAnswer}<p/><p>Explanation: ${element.explanation}</p>`;
    }
  });

  result_container.textContent = `Your score is: ${score} out of ${questions}`;
  result_div.style.display = "block"; // Ensure result div is displayed
});

// Reset quiz functionality
reset_quiz.addEventListener("click", function () {
  // Clear all radio button selections
  document.querySelectorAll("input[type=radio]").forEach((element) => {
    element.checked = false;
  });

  // Hide all explanations and clear their content
  document.querySelectorAll(".explanation").forEach((element) => {
    element.style.display = "none";
    element.innerHTML = "";
  });

  // Hide the result container and clear its content
  result_div.style.display = "none";
  result_container.innerHTML = ""; // Clear the result text content
});
